export default {
  id: 'low_1006_4_1a',
  name: '상용한자(4학년-1/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '加', answer: ['더할 가', 'くわ(わる)、くわ(える)', 'か'] },
    { question: '街', answer: ['거리 가', 'まち', 'がい、かい'] },
    { question: '各', answer: ['각각 각', 'おのおの', 'かく'] },
    { question: '覚', answer: ['깨달을 각', 'おぼ(える)、さ(ます)、さ(める)', 'かく'] },
    { question: '康', answer: ['편안할 강', '편안할', 'こう'] },
    { question: '改', answer: ['고칠 개', 'あらた(める)、あらた(まる)', 'かい'] },
    { question: '挙', answer: ['들 거', 'あ(げる)、あ(がる)', 'きょ'] },
    { question: '建', answer: ['세울 건', 'た(てる)、た(つ)', 'けん、こん'] },
    { question: '健', answer: ['굳셀 건', 'すこ(やか)', 'けん'] },
    { question: '欠', answer: ['이지러질 결', 'か(ける)、か(く)', 'けつ'] },
    { question: '結', answer: ['맺을 결', 'むす(ぶ)、ゆ(う)、ゆ(わえる)', 'けつ'] },
    { question: '景', answer: ['볕 경', '볕', 'けい'] },
    { question: '径', answer: ['지름길 경', '지름길', 'けい'] },
    { question: '競', answer: ['다툴 경', 'きそ(う)、せ(る)', 'きょう、けい'] },
    { question: '鏡', answer: ['거울 경', 'かがみ', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '季', answer: ['계절 계', '계절', 'き'] },
    { question: '械', answer: ['기계 계', '기계', 'かい'] },
    { question: '固', answer: ['굳을 고', 'かた(める)、かた(まる)、かた(い)', 'こ'] },
    { question: '告', answer: ['고할 고', 'つ(げる)', 'こく'] },
    { question: '功', answer: ['공 공', '공', 'こう、く'] },
    { question: '共', answer: ['한가지 공', 'とも', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '果', answer: ['실과 과', 'は(たす)、は(てる)、は(て)', 'か'] },
    { question: '課', answer: ['공부할 과', '공부할', 'か'] },
    { question: '官', answer: ['벼슬 관', '벼슬', 'かん'] },
    { question: '管', answer: ['대롱 관', 'くだ', 'かん'] },
    { question: '関', answer: ['관계할 관', 'せき、かか(わる)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '観', answer: ['볼 관', '볼', 'かん'] },
    { question: '求', answer: ['구할 구', 'もと(める)', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '救', answer: ['구원할 구', 'すく(う)', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '軍', answer: ['군사 군', '군사', 'ぐん'] },
    { question: '郡', answer: ['고을 군', '고을', 'ぐん'] },
    { question: '極', answer: ['극진할 극', 'きわ(める)、きわ(まる)、きわ(み)', 'きょく、ごく'] },
    { question: '給', answer: ['줄 급', '줄', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '紀', answer: ['벼리 기', '벼리', 'き'] },
    { question: '器', answer: ['그릇 기', 'うつわ', 'き'] },
    { question: '機', answer: ['베틀 기', 'はた', 'き'] },
    { question: '旗', answer: ['깃발 기', 'はた', 'き'] },
    { question: '念', answer: ['생각 념', '생각', 'ねん'] },
    { question: '努', answer: ['힘쓸 노', 'つと(める)', 'ど'] },
    { question: '単', answer: ['홑 단', '홑', 'たん'] },
    { question: '堂', answer: ['집 당', '집', 'どう'] },
    { question: '達', answer: ['통달할 달', '통달할', 'たつ'] },
    { question: '隊', answer: ['무리 대', '무리', 'たい'] },
    { question: '帯', answer: ['띠 대', 'お(びる)、おび', 'たい'] },
    { question: '徒', answer: ['무리 도', '무리', 'と'] },
    { question: '毒', answer: ['독 독', '독', 'どく'] },
    { question: '働', answer: ['일할 동', 'はたら(く)', 'どう'] },
    { question: '得', answer: ['얻을 득', 'え(る)、う(る)', 'とく'] },
    { question: '灯', answer: ['등불 등', 'ひ', 'とう'] },
    { question: '冷', answer: ['찰 랭', 'つめ(たい)、ひ(える)、ひ(や)、ひ(やす)、ひや(かす)、さ(める)、さ(ます)', 'れい'] },
    { question: '量', answer: ['헤아릴 량', 'はか(る)', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '良', answer: ['어질 량', 'よ(い)', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '歴', answer: ['지낼 력', '지낼', 'れき'] },
    { question: '連', answer: ['잇닿을 련', 'つ(れ)る、つら(なる)、つら(ねる)', 'れん'] },
    { question: '令', answer: ['하여금 령', '하여금', 'れい'] },
    { question: '例', answer: ['법식 례', 'たと(える)', 'れい'] },
    { question: '労', answer: ['일할 로', '일할', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '老', answer: ['늙을 로', 'お(いる)、ふ(ける)', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '録', answer: ['기록할 록', '기록할', 'ろく'] },
    { question: '料', answer: ['헤아릴 료', '헤아릴', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '類', answer: ['무리 류', 'たぐい', 'るい'] },
    { question: '陸', answer: ['뭍 륙', '뭍', 'りく'] },
    { question: '輪', answer: ['바퀴 륜', 'わ', 'りん'] },
    { question: '利', answer: ['이로울 리', 'き(く)', 'り'] },
    { question: '満', answer: ['찰 만', 'み(ちる)、み(たす)', 'まん'] },
    { question: '末', answer: ['끝 말', 'すえ', 'まつ、ばつ'] },
    { question: '望', answer: ['바랄 망', 'のぞ(む)', 'ぼう、もう'] },
    { question: '梅', answer: ['매화 매', 'うめ', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '脈', answer: ['줄기 맥', '줄기', 'みゃく'] },
    { question: '牧', answer: ['칠 목', 'まき', 'ぼく'] },
    { question: '無', answer: ['없을 무', 'な(い)', 'む、ぶ'] },
    { question: '未', answer: ['아닐 미', '아닐', 'み'] },
    { question: '民', answer: ['백성 민', 'たみ', 'みん'] },
    { question: '博', answer: ['넓을 박', '넓을', 'はく、ばく'] },
    { question: '飯', answer: ['밥 반', 'めし', 'はん'] },
    { question: '法', answer: ['법 법', '법', 'ほう、はっ、ほっ'] },
    { question: '辺', answer: ['가 변', 'あた(り)、べ', 'へん'] },
    { question: '変', answer: ['변할 변', 'か(わる)、か(える)', 'へん'] },
    { question: '別', answer: ['나눌 별', 'わか(れる)', 'べつ'] },
    { question: '兵', answer: ['군사 병', '군사', 'へい、ひょう'] },
    { question: '夫', answer: ['지아비 부', 'おっと', 'ふ、ふう'] },
    { question: '付', answer: ['줄 부', 'つ(く)、つ(ける)', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '府', answer: ['마을 부', '마을', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '副', answer: ['버금 부', '버금', 'ふく'] },
    { question: '粉', answer: ['가루 분', 'こ、こな', 'ふん'] },
    { question: '不', answer: ['아닐 불(부)', '아닐', 'ふ、ぶ'] },
    { question: '飛', answer: ['날 비', 'と(ぶ)、と(ばす)', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '費', answer: ['쓸 비', 'つい(やす)、つい(える)', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '士', answer: ['선비 사', '선비', 'し'] },
    { question: '史', answer: ['사기 사', '사기', 'し'] },
    { question: '司', answer: ['맡을 사', '맡을', 'し'] },
    { question: '辞', answer: ['말씀 사', 'や(める)', 'じ'] },
    { question: '産', answer: ['낳을 산', 'う(む)、う(まれる)、う(ぶ)', 'さん'] },
    { question: '散', answer: ['흩을 산', 'ち(る)、ち(らす)、ち(らかす)、ち(らかる)', 'さん'] },
    { question: '殺', answer: ['죽일 살', 'ころ(す)', 'さつ、さい、せつ'] },
    { question: '象', answer: ['코끼리 상', '코끼리', 'しょう、ぞう'] },
    { question: '賞', answer: ['상줄 상', '상줄', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '席', answer: ['자리 석', '자리', 'せき'] },
    { question: '選', answer: ['가릴 선', 'えら(ぶ)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '説', answer: ['말씀 설/달랠 세', 'と(く)', 'せつ、ぜい'] }
  ]
}
